<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Jacek's Blog</title>
        <link>https://galowicz.de</link>
        <description><![CDATA[This blog is about programming]]></description>
        <atom:link href="https://galowicz.de/feed.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>Single-Command Server Bootstrapping</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/04/05/single-command-server-bootstrap</link>
    <description><![CDATA[When you spin up a new VM or bare metal server at some cloud provider, what isthe fastest and easiest way to get the server to run a certain configuration?In this article, I show how to do the partitioning, formatting, and installing afully configured NixOS, starting from a random rescuesystem, in 5 minutes and with literally a single command:nixos-anywhere.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/04/05/single-command-server-bootstrap</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Quick VMs with NixOS</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/03/13/quick-vms-with-nixos</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Very often during development, it is useful to run your code in a scenario thatis as near to a final deployment as possible, but not in some cloud environmentwhere it’s hard to change specific parts without going through the full CI/CDchain.I find it very useful to quickly build, run, iterate, rebuild, and rerun VMswith NixOS Linux on my development machines.This week I demonstrate this aspect of my workflow with NixOS.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/03/13/quick-vms-with-nixos</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Simple Project Documentation with MkDocs, PlantUML, and PlantUML-C4 Integration</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/20/simple-documentation-with-mkdocs-plantuml-c4-integration</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Technical documentation is tedious but important for every project.Hence, it should be easy to create, extend, and keep up to date.I tend to use the open-source tool MkDocs forprojects.In this blog article, I share how to extend and package this tool with niceplugins that make documentation easier.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/20/simple-documentation-with-mkdocs-plantuml-c4-integration</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Simple(r) Heterogeneous Mapping of Records in Purescript</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/13/purescript-heterogeneous-map</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Two weeks ago, I blogged about the automatic heterogeneous zipping of recordsin PureScript.The code was longer than the manual version but at least less error-prone.After learning how to do it this way, I present a neat little library (not mine)that provides all the benefits without the downsides.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/13/purescript-heterogeneous-map</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Constructing Parameterized Matrices with GNU Octave</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/06/constructing-parameterized-matrices-with-gnu-octave</link>
    <description><![CDATA[This week I was dealing with image processing and linear algebra, and I neededa quick derivation of a specific kind of matrix.With GNU Octave to the rescue, this cost me only a few minutes!This article represents my notes from this little journey from the mathematicalderivation of the matrix and the symbolic solution that I then ported to C++.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/02/06/constructing-parameterized-matrices-with-gnu-octave</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Interpolation of Records of Values in Purescript</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/30/purescript-interpolation-of-records</link>
    <description><![CDATA[This article is about a little interesting detour that I made in one of mypersonal projects:How to use strong type systems to generically apply a binary mathematicalfunction on all items of a possibly nested record.The code provides interesting insights into other languages with similar typesystems.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/30/purescript-interpolation-of-records</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mixed C++ Monorepo Project Structure Development and Build Workflow</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/23/mixed-cpp-monorepo-project</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Most big C++ projects lack a clear structure:They consist of multiple modules, but it is not as easy to create individuallybuildable, portable, testable, and reusable libraries from them, as it is withprojects written in Rust, Go, Haskell, etc.In this article, I propose a C++ project structure using CMake that makes iteasy to have incremental monorepo builds and a nice modular structure at thesame time.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/23/mixed-cpp-monorepo-project</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>(Qt)Quick C++ Project Setup with Nix</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/16/cpp-qt-qml-nix-setup</link>
    <description><![CDATA[I never install toolchains globally on my systems.Instead, every project comes with its own nix file that describes the completedevelopment toolchain versions and dependencies.This way, fresh checkouts always build the same way on every machine.This week I would like to show you how I set up a C++ project with the Qt Quickframework, and how to package the app and make it runnable for other nix users.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/16/cpp-qt-qml-nix-setup</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Automatic Testing of Display Resolution and Frame Drop Detection</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/09/automatic-testing-of-display-resolution-and-frame-drop-detection</link>
    <description><![CDATA[This week, I like to share a project with you that started as a very interestingchallenge and developed into an interdisciplinary, productive, and funexperience:A fully automatic multi-display end-to-end customer test prototype.In the end, it was surprising to see what parts of the code the most effortwent into.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/09/automatic-testing-of-display-resolution-and-frame-drop-detection</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Book Review: Basic Forms of Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/02/book-review-basic-forms-of-anxiety</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Software engineering, or generally IT jobs, are highly social because all bigsoftware projects or products are built by teams of professionals.When humans work with humans, all kinds of conflict can emerge, and they areoften not as easy to fix as IT problems, especially in distributed teams withless offline human interaction.This article is about Fritz Riemann’s book “Anxiety”,which answers the question “What do people fear and how do they cope with it?”.]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://galowicz.de/2023/01/02/book-review-basic-forms-of-anxiety</guid>
    <dc:creator>Jacek Galowicz</dc:creator>
</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
